(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
- I'm Amira.
- Hey Amira, how are you today?
- I'm doing great, what about you?
- I'm doing pretty good.
I'm excited about this lesson
that you have for us today.
- Yeah, so it's actually a
very, very useful lesson.
It's about someone asking
his boss for an assistant.
- Oh, okay, an assistant.
What's an assistant?
- Well, it's someone who helps
you with your work around the office.
- Okay, great.
So let's listen to this dialogue and
when we come back, we'll take a look
at all the interesting and
useful vocabulary that you'll find.
(upbeat music)
- Like I told you before, we just don't
have the resources to hire you an assistant.
- I understand that, but
the fact is we're understaffed.
- The timing is just not right.
- The economy's bad and it's
too risky to take on new staff.
- Yeah, I guess you're right.
Here's an idea, what if we hire an intern?
She would take some of
the weight off my shoulders.
- She?
- Yeah, you know, a recent graduate,
she could give me a
hand with some of these
projects and we could
keep our costs down.
- That sounds reasonable.
Let me see what I can do.
Toni, I'd like to introduce
you to your new assistant.
- Okay, great, let's meet her.
- Hi, I'm Adam.
- Oh, hi, I'm Toni.
- And we're back.
Toni, he's surprised, huh?
- Yeah, he's a, I don't know
why though, he's surprised.
I think we should talk
about that a little bit later.
- Yes, for now, let's look at some
interesting vocabulary and phrases here.
- Marco, I know you've chosen one for us.
- Yeah, the first one that I want
to take a look at is resources.
- Resources.
- And that means in
this text, basically money.
- Right.
- So the office doesn't have enough money.
- Okay, I've chosen another interesting
word for you and that's understaffed.
- Understaffed.
- Now, understaffed means that they
don't have enough people working there.
- They don't have enough workers.
- Right, they don't have enough employees.
- Perfect, okay.
The next one is timing is just not right.
- The timing is just not right.
- Okay, let's listen to how
we can use this entire phrase
in a different situation so then
we can understand what it means.
Let's listen.
(upbeat music)
- I was gonna sell my house,
but the timing is just not right.
- Honey, I think we should have a baby.
- The timing is just not right.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, great, I guess that makes it clear.
- Yes, actually it's very obvious that
it means that it's just not a good time.
- Right, perfect.
- I have another interesting phrase
for you, which is, "Wait off my shoulders.
" - Wait off my shoulders.
- Wait off my shoulders.
- So to take wait off my shoulders
is another way of saying to
help me with my work or to take
some of my work away from me.
- If you have a lot of things to do
and I come and help you, that means
that I took some of the
weight off your shoulders.
- Yes.
- Let's look at the next phrase that
we have here and it's give me a hand.
- Give me a hand.
- Okay, now this is not literal,
it's not that I'm gonna give
you somebody's hand, right?
Let's listen to some examples and then we
can come back and explain what it means.
(upbeat music)
- Can you give me a hand with these boxes?
- Neil, I'll need you to give me
a hand with the sales reports.
- And here, let me give you
a hand with your suitcase.
(upbeat music)
- All right, give me a hand is another
way of saying help or to help out.
- Exactly, to help out.
- Right. - Perfect.
- Now, the last phrase
we're going to look at
here in this dialogue
is keep our costs down.
- Keep our costs down.
- So to keep our costs down means
to try and not spend so much money.
- Exactly, many companies, for example,
now control how much printing you do.
- Yes.
- Right, to keep the cost down of paper.
- Yeah, so in other words, they do
not want to have unnecessary spending.
- Perfect.
Okay, I think it's time for
us to listen to this dialogue
one more time, but I want everyone to listen
and see why Tony is surprised at the end
when he meets his intern,
when he meets his assistant.
- Like I told you before, we just don't
have the resources to hire you an assistant.
- I understand that, but the
fact is, we're understaffed.
The timing is just not right.
The economy's bad and it's
too risky to take on new staff.
- Yeah, I guess you're right.
Here's an idea, what if we hire an intern?
She would take some of
the weight off my shoulders.
- She?
- Yeah, you know, a recent graduate,
she could get me a hand with some of these
projects and we could keep our costs down.
- That sounds reasonable.
Let me see what I can do.
- Tony, I'd like to introduce
you to your new assistant.
- Okay, great, let's meet her.
- Hi, I'm Adam.
- Oh, hi, I'm Tony.
- Well, you know, Marco, I think that Tony
was really surprised because he was
kind of hoping to have a female intern?
- Yeah, I think that's exactly
what he was expecting.
Maybe this guy is a little bit sexist.
He thought that an intern should be a girl.
But instead, he was--
- Instead, he got Adam.
- Exactly, and it looks
like Adam is really big
and really tall because
he's got that deep voice.
- Right, an intern, Marco, do
you want to elaborate on that?
- Working at a company with a very
low salary or sometimes no salary at all,
but what you're gaining is experience
and you're learning a lot of things.
Everyone who has been
an intern or had an intern,
knows that sometimes they
are not treated all that well,
sometimes they just serve coffee
or they have to do paperwork.
- Or like photocopying, saying exactly.
- Yeah.
- But some internships
are really, really cool
and some are really good
experiences for learning.
- Yeah, definitely.
Actually, I know a friend of
mine, she used to work as an
intern in one of those really
big companies and she told me
that she has gained so
much experience doing that.
- Yeah, I mean, even if you don't get paid,
the experience that you get is really good
and that just opens doors
for maybe getting another job
or sometimes the
interns get hired by the
company to stay because
they do such a good job.
- Yeah, I think that's
mostly the case, huh?
- Yeah, that happened to
me once I started working
as an intern and after three months, I was
hired by the company, so it does happen.
- Do you did a good job?
- Yeah, of course.
(laughs) All right, folks,
we're out of time today.
I hope that you enjoyed our lesson
and we'll be back tomorrow
with another really cool
and really interesting
lesson from EnglishPod.
Don't forget to come to our
website at www.EnglishPod.
com where you'll find some really
great and interesting resources
to help you learn and
improve your English even more.
- Yes, you should definitely do that.
And Marco and I would
love to receive your comments
and suggestions that you can
leave on our community forum.
But for now, it's time for us to say bye.
(upbeat music)